Doubt
I've got to admit that I was rather surprised, Ryuuga, to be invited to play tennis with you so that we could get to know each other better.
しかしおどろいだよ流河
親睦を深める為に、突然テニスなんて…
Has this caused a problem for you?
迷惑でしたか？
Not at all... but were you aware of how skilled I am when you asked me to play?
いや
でも僕の実力、知ってて言い出したのか？
Not at all... but were you aware of how skilled I am when you asked me to play?
That's okay, Yagami-kun.
大丈夫です、夜神君
私はイギリスのジュニアチャンピオンだったことがあります
I used to be the Junior Champion of England.
If I ask him, "Does that mean you're English?", will he think that I'm attempting to question him because I am Kira?
ここで「国籍はイギリス？」と聞けば、
キラだから探りを入れてると思うのか
まぁいい、試してみるか
Never mind. I'll just give it a try.
Were you brought up in England?
流河はイギリス育ち？
I've lived in England for about five years.
イギリスには五年ほど住んでいましたが、
But I wouldn't worry about it, there's nothing about that which will compromise my identity as L.
安心してください、
そこから L の素性が割れるようなことは絶対ありません
But I wouldn't worry about it, there's nothing about that which will compromise my identity as L.
Oh, I see...
あっそう…
You're fine with the winner being whoever wins the first set of six games, I assume?
では六ゲーム１セット先勝したほうが勝ちでいいですね
I've got it.
わかった
This is strictly a friendly tennis match.
これはあくまでも親睦のテニス
I won't be able to use this to help me judge whether he's Kira or not.
キラかどうかの判断裁量にはなりえない
But Kira does supposedly hate to lose...
しかしキラは負けず嫌い…
Fifteen - love
１５－０です
Hey, hey, Ryuuga, you're getting serious already?
おいおい流河、いきなり本気かよ
He who takes the initiative wins.
先手必勝です
What do you mean, "you can't say"?!
言えないとはどういうことだ
I'm extremely sorry.
申し訳ありません、
Under L's orders, I can't tell anyone outside the Investigative Headquarters, even if you are the Deputy Chief.
L の指示で捜査本部外の者にはたとえ次長でも…
You can't even tell me what you're doing, and where?!
今どこで何をしているのか、それすらもか？
I'm extremely sorry...
申し訳ありません
Say, Yagami. It's already been four months since this case first came to light.
なぁ夜神、
この事件が明るみになってから、もう四ヶ月以上も経つ
The public believe that the police are incompetent, and that L is incompetent.
世間では警察も無能、L も無能
お言葉ですが次長
Excuse me for saying this, Deputy, but can you honestly say that a police force that turns tail and runs scared of Kira is "competent"?
キラを恐れて尻尾を巻く警察が、有能だと言えるのでしょうか
I'm sure you're well aware of how many of us remained at Headquarters.
次長は、今の捜査本部が何人になってるのかご存知のはず
If you're so concerned with public opinion, just make sure they don't find out the truth; that the majority of the police force, and especially the leaders, have fled from Kira!
世間でお気になさるなら、幹部を始めとする大部分が、
キラから逃げたと言う事実を知られないように努めてください！
Excuse me.
…失礼します
夜神
Yagami.
What's L like?
L はどうなんだ、
Can we trust him?
信用できるのか？
He's far more capable than we are.
我々よりは有能だと思われます、
今も命を掛けて自ら動いています
Even now, he's making the moves personally, placing his own life on the line.
こいつらアマチュアか、
Are they meant to be amateurs?
Who the hell are they?
何者なんだ
It's Yagami Light and Ryuuga Hideki.
夜神月と流河旱樹ですよ
Both of them enrolled with the top grades.
今年、成績トップで入学した二人です
Don't worry, Yagami.
安心しろ夜神
Although Kira hates to lose, the majority of people would want to win in a match, whether they are Kira or not.
キラは負けず嫌いだが、
キラでなくとも試合に勝ちたいと思うのが大多数だ
Although Kira hates to lose, the majority of people would want to win in a match, whether they are Kira or not.
Going all out for a win is in keeping with Kira's character? Is this it?!
ムキになって勝ち抜くとキラっぽい…か？
But if I purposely lose for that reason — thinking that going for a complete victory is Kira-like — then my purposely losing will also be Kira-like, won't it?
だからと言ってわざと負ければ、
ムキになって勝ち抜くとキラっぽいと思われるから
But if I purposely lose for that reason — thinking that going for a complete victory is Kira-like — then my purposely losing will also be Kira-like, won't it?
わざと負けるところがまだキラっぽい…だろ
It all comes down to the same thing.
結局同じこと
アイツのこのテニスでプロファイルなんてするわけがない、
There's no way he can use this match to create a profile of me.
The objective of this match lies elsewhere.
このテニスの目的は他にある
That's why, even at tennis... I will win this too!
だからテニスでも…
僕が勝つ！
See. I knew you would want to win.
ほうら、勝ちにきた
Game count, four games all!
ゲームカウント、４ゲームズオール
へへ、いつの間にか、
Somehow, both a referee and a linesman have appeared.
審判やラインズマンまでいるぞ
Senpai!
先輩！
ん？
I thought I'd heard the name Yagami Light before, so I went and looked it up.
夜神月ってどこかで聞いたことあると思って調べたら、
Turns out he was the Junior Champion in 2002 and 2003!
二千二年と三年の中学生チャンピオンです
During the award ceremony, in his third year of Junior High, he announced; "I'm quitting this hobby at the end of Junior High".
十三の時の表彰式で、「遊びは中学まで」と宣言して、
それっきり何の大会にも出ていません
Since then, he hasn't participated in any tournaments.
ねぇねぇ、
Hey, hey! Ryuuga-kun is managing to hold his own against a Junior Champion, so what does that make him?!
じゃあその中学チャンピオンと
互角に戦ってる流河君ってなんなの？
I can read you, Yagami Light.
読めるぞ、夜神月、
I can read your feelings.
お前の気持ちが…
There's no way our friendship is going to deepen thanks to this tennis match.
こんなテニスで親睦が高まるはずがない
This is just a ritual formality allowing us to acknowledge that we became better friends.
これはお互いが、「深まった」と了承しあうの為の儀式だ！
You believe that I'm using this match to advance my preparations in breaking you.
このテニスをしたことで、
お前は私がまた一歩を前に踏み込むを準備したと考える
I bet that you'll try to make me say something that only Kira will know.
そしてお前は僕に、
キラしか知らない事を…言わせようとするだろう！
First you'll state that you need to know what information I have on Kira in order to trust me.
しかし、お前は先にこっちの捜査状況などを見せ、
まず「自分を信用させろ」と言ってくるだろ
If we're going to talk about the Kira case, I'll have to at least request proof that he's actually the one in charge at the moment.
キラ事件の話をするのなら、
少なくとも今、
キラ事件に指揮を執っているのがアイツであることの証明を、
僕が求めるのは必然だ！
That's why... you'll request that I... provide significant proof from a third-party that you are L.
だから、これからお前が私に要求してくるのは…
お前を L だと証明する、有力な第三者との接見
つまり…
Basically... to take me to the Investigative Headquarters.
Basically... to take you to the Investigative Headquarters.
捜査本部に連れて行くこと！
No matter what the situation, you can't win solely by defending.
どんなことでも、守っているだけでは勝てない
勝つには…攻めること！
To win, you need to attack!
Game, set; won by Yagami!
Game set 　　　　　　won by
ゲームセット、ウォンバイ夜神
Game, set; won by Yagami!
Six games to four.
6-4
Six Games to Four
Wow!
Amazing!
Wow! Amazing!
You're as good as I expected you to be. I lost.
さすが夜神君、負けました
僕も久し振りに本気を出したよ、流河
That's the first time that I've gotten serious over something in a while, Ryuuga.
I'm thirsty, and I have a favor I'd like to ask of you, so shall we stop for a drink after this?
喉も渇いたし、流河に頼みたい事もあるから、
この後お茶しないか？
Well, seeing that I lost the game, ask away.
ゲームに負けたことですし、
聞けることなら何でもお聞きします
Well, seeing that I lost the game, ask away.
But there's just one thing I got to mention first.
しかし、その前に私も一つ言っておくことがあります
What?
なに？
I suspect that you may be Kira.
私は夜神君をキラじゃないかと疑っているんです、
If that's not a problem, feel free to ask me anything.
それでも聞けることなら、なんでもお聞きします
ははは、僕がキラ？
Me, Kira?
Well, when I say "suspect", it's only about 1%.
いえ、疑っていると言っても、１パーセントぐらいです
More importantly, I'd like to confirm both that you're not Kira, and also the rumors regarding your skills of deduction, before asking you to help with the investigation.
それよりも、夜神君がキラでない事と、
素晴らしい推理力を持つことを確信できたなら、
是非、捜査に協力して頂きたいを思っています
1%, huh?
１パーセントか…
That's an excellent way of putting it.
上手い言い方だ
If they suspect me even in the slightest, they won't allow me near their Headquarters even if I ask.
たとえほんの少しでも疑われているなら、
僕が捜査本部の者に合わせろと言ってもダメだというだろ
You've made the first move.
空気を先にさされたということだ
…やられた
You've got me.
This café is a favorite of mine.
この喫茶店は僕のお気に入りでね
If you sit here, people won't be able to overhear your conversations.
この席に座れば、人に会話を聞かれることもない
Thanks for showing me this place, it's nice.
良いところを教えて頂きました
You don't need to worry about sitting like that here.
ここなら、その座り方もそんなに気にすることもないしね
I've got to sit like this.
私はこの座り方でないとダメなんです
If I sit normally, my investigative abilities decrease by 40%.
一般的な座り方をすると、推理力が４０パーセント減です
So, what's this favor you wanted to ask of me?
で、私に頼みたいことって…
Oh, I think I'll leave that until you've confirmed that I'm not Kira.
ああ、それは僕がキラじゃないと分った時でいいよ
流河のほうからすきに話してくれ
You can go first. Ask me anything.
Okay. I don't mean to be rude, but would you mind if I tested your skills of deduction?
では失礼とは思いますが、
夜神君の推理力をテストしてみもいいでしょうか
Okay. I don't mean to be rude, but would you mind if I tested your skills of deduction?
No, go right ahead.
ああいいよ、面白そうだ
It sounds fun.
Okay then. First, I'd like you to take a look at these.
ではまず、こちらを御覧になってみてください
These three are photos of letters; it's thought that Kira controlled criminals in a prison, and then, before they died, had them write these.
この三枚は、キラが刑務所内の犯罪者を操って、
死ぬ前に書かせたと思われる文書の写真です
Please let me hear your opinions about them.
これについて夜神君の意見を聞かせてください
Interesting.
面白いね
Honestly, this is child's play.
まったく、子供騙しだ
There are print numbers on the back of these.
写真の裏にプリントナンバーが入っている
If I create the sentence "L, did you know Shinigami only eat apples?" without even looking at them, it'll deepen your suspicions, right?
これに気付かず、
「 L 知っているか、死神はリンゴしか食べない」と言う
If I create the sentence "L, did you know Shinigami only eat apples?" without even looking at them, it'll deepen your suspicions, right?
キラが読ませた通りの文書を作ったら…
キラ濃厚ってわけか…
だがこの程度の暗号を解いたどころで、
But just because I'm able to solve this simple puzzle, it won't prove that I am Kira.
僕がキラだという証明にはならない
If Kira can truly manipulate not only the time of death, but also the actions of people prior to death, it'd be amazing.
キラが死だけでなく、
その人間の行動を操れるとしたら、すごい事実だね
If Kira can truly manipulate not only the time of death, but also the actions of people prior to death, it'd be amazing.
In fact, these messages contain hidden messages that seem to be teasing you.
しかもこれには、
L をからかうような文書が暗号化されている…
In fact, these messages contain hidden messages that seem to be teasing you.
If you take only the top letters from each sentence, and read from left to right, it creates another sentence.
それぞれの文書の一番上の文字だけ取って並べ変えると、
まだ文書になる
Arranging it in the most natural way, it would be... "L did you know Shinigami only eat apples", I guess.
違和感のない分と言うと…そうだな
「L 知っているか、死神はリンゴしか食べない」…かな？
でも、写真の裏にプリントナンバーが入っている
But there are also print numbers on the back of these photos.
その順に並べ変えると…
If you place them in that order... "L, did you know that if they only eat apples, Shinigami",
「 L 知っているか、リンゴしか食べない、死神は」だ
but this seems rather unnatural, and I find it hard to believe that this is what Kira wanted to say.
少し不自然で、
キラが L にこう読ませようとしたとは考えにくいけどね
Incorrect.
…不正解です
え？
There is in fact a fourth photo.
実は四枚目の写真があるんです
If you include this, it becomes something like this...
これを加えるとこうなります
"L, did you know that if they only eat apples, Shinigami have red hands."
「 L 知ってるか、リンゴしか食べない死神は、手が赤い」
The fourth one is fake.
フェイクだ
この四枚目は、僕が犯罪者に書かせた物でもない
It isn't something that I've made a criminal write.
Is he stupid or something?
馬鹿かコイツ
But my theory is perfect if there are only three photos.
しかし三枚だけなら、僕の推理で完璧じゃないか
No, it was incorrect.
完璧ではありません
There are in fact four. It would have been correct if you had accounted for that.
事実四枚あったのですから、そこまで推理して完璧です
Despite the fact that the sentence didn't end, you decided that there were only three photos, and were unable to deduce that there may have been a fourth.
夜神君は文書が知りきれになるにもかかわらず
三枚しかないと決めつけ、
四枚目を推理できなかった、これも事実です
That is a fact.
You...
コイツ…
I get it. He's not trying to test my deduction skills; he's analyzing my reactions.
なるほど、これは推理力ではなく、
反応を見ているんだ
これ以上を食ってかかったらコイツの思う壷だ…
If I try to challenge him further, I'll be doing exactly what he wants me to...
Yeah... I wasn't able to deduce that much.
そこまで推理できなかったな…
Either way, they aren't messages that will bring us any closer to Kira.
まぁどっちにしろ、キラに迫れる文書ではないしね
It's not like Shinigami really exist.
死神なんているわけないし
Yagami-kun, if you were L, and were with someone you suspected might be Kira, how would you go about proving it?
ではもし、夜神君が L だとして、
キラである可能性のある者に相対したら、
Yagami-kun, if you were L, and were with someone you suspected might be Kira, how would you go about proving it?
どうやって確かめますか？
I'd make them say something that hasn't been broadcast to the public; something that only Kira would know.
一般には報道されていない、
キラにしか知り得ない事を相手にしゃべらせる
I'd make them say something that hasn't been broadcast to the public; something that only Kira would know.
What you are trying to do right now.
今流河がしていることだ
Amazing. I've asked many detectives this question, yet most of them need at least a few minutes before they can answer.
すごいですね
今と同じ質問を何人かの刑事にしたのですが、
答えるまでに数分考えるものが殆ど
You however, were instantaneously able to think as Kira would if they were confronted with someone investigating them.
しかし夜神君は、
瞬迅に捜査する者と話をする時のキラの立場で考えられた
You however, were instantaneously able to think as Kira would if they were confronted with someone investigating them.
Your sense of reasoning is amazing.
すごいです、夜神君の推理力は
はは…あまり卓越した考え方をすると、
疑いが濃くなるみたいじゃないか
If my ideas are too good, it seems like you'll get even more suspicious!
Yes, by 3%.
はい、３パーセントに
But at the same time, my desire to have you investigate with us has also grown. Even if you are Kira.
しかしその分、
一緒に捜査して欲しいという気持ちも強くなりました
But at the same time, my desire to have you investigate with us has also grown. Even if you are Kira.
私はたとえ夜神君がキラであっても、
I'm in a position where it would still benefit me to have you investigate with us.
夜神君に捜査協力してもらえればいい立場にあるんです
Do you understand this logic?
この理屈分ります？
If I help with the investigation, there's a potential for it to move forward.
僕が協力すれば、捜査も進むかもしれないと同時に、
Also, if I'm Kira, I might somehow give myself away.
もしキラならぼろを出すかもしれない
つまり、捜査と取り調べを一度にできる
In other words, you can both investigate and interrogate at the same time.
I think that's a good idea... but I think that you're misunderstanding something here.
いい考えだと思うよ
でも何か勘違いしていないか流河
It's true that I'm interested in the Kira case, and that I also enjoy investigating as a hobby, but I'm not Kira, and I don't want to be killed by Kira.
確かに僕はキラ事件に興味を持ち、趣味で推理をしているが、
僕はキラじゃないから、キラに殺されるのはごめんだ
第一、流河だってキラじゃない証拠は何もないんだ、
Besides, you don't have any proof that you're not Kira!
In that case, it'd be strange for only one of us to be investigating the other.
片方が取り調べ紛いなことをするのはおかしいだろう
There's nothing to prove that either of us aren't Kira, but since you claim to be L, we should at least be able to prove that.
どっちもキラじゃないなんて証明はできない
しかし、流河が L だと言うのなら、その証明はできるはずだ
There's nothing to prove that either of us aren't Kira, but since you claim to be L, we should at least be able to prove that.
We could for example get my father or another member of the investigation to identity you in front of me.
例えば、捜査本部の一員や父に、
L 本人だと僕の目の前で証明してもらう事だ
If that's not possible, then I can't investigate with you.
それが無理なら、一緒に捜査することはできない
You're talking a fair amount, Yagami Light.
よくしゃべるな夜神月、
Typical of someone who doesn't like to lose.
負けず嫌いの典型だ
7%.
７パーセント、もしかして本当に…
Maybe it really is...
I never said anything about not allowing you to meet the people at the Investigative Headquarters.
捜査本部の者に合わせないなんて、
そんなこと一度も言ってませんよ
Huh?!
えっ？
Currently I'm working both with your father and the others at the Investigative Headquarters.
今私は捜査本部で、
夜神君のお父さん達と共に捜査をしています
So, if I take you to the Investigative Headquarters, I can get you to cooperate with our investigation.
その捜査本部に夜神君を連れて行けば捜査に協力して頂ける…
Have I understood that correctly?
そう解釈していいんですね
What the hell is this guy thinking?!
…何考えてるんだコイツ
Excuse me.
失礼します
あ…僕も
Me too.
Yes.
はい
Ryuuzaki! Something terrible has happened!
竜崎、大変なことに…
Light! Your father...
月、お父さんが…
Yagami-kun!!
夜神君！
Father? A heart attack?!
父が…心臓発作…
Well, I'll see you tomorrow, and I'll bring some essentials.
じゃあ、また明日
必要なものを持ってきますから
月、あと頼むわよ
I'll leave the rest up to you, Light.
ああ
Okay.
Are you sure you're just overworked?
本当にただの過労なんだろうな
Yeah. When I first went down I thought that it might be Kira... but it's alright.
ああ…正直倒れる瞬間、キラかと思ったが大丈夫だ
I've probably been overdoing it recently.
ここ最近、少し無理をしたようだ
All the more because you knew that your son was suspected of being Kira.
さらに息子さんがキラだと疑われていたのでは尚更です
You even told my father that?!
そんな事まで父に…
Yes, I've told him everything.
はい、全て話してあります、
Even the fact that I'm L.
私が L であることも…
He's right. He is L.
そうだ、彼が L だ
We call him "Ryuuzaki" so that outsiders don't realize it, but without a doubt, he is L.
第三者にはわからぬよう、我々は竜崎と呼んでいるが、
間違いなく L だ
He's the real L.
コイツが本物の L …父が言ってるんだ、
That's what father is saying.
少なくとも今まで警察を動かしてきた L だ
So if nothing else, he's the L that's been controlling the police.
コイツと本部の人間を全て消せば…
If I can erase him and everyone else on the investigation... wait. It's not going to be that simple.
いや、そんな単純ではないだろう
焦ることもない、ここからはじっくり探れば…
There's no reason to rush.
I just need to investigate this situation thoroughly.
とにかく今は、父を心配する夜神月だ
Either way, right now, I've got to be the Yagami Light who's worried about his father.
で、竜崎
So, Ryuuzaki, have your suspicions about my son lessened now that you've had a chance to talk to him?
息子と話をしてみて、疑いは晴れたのか
You say "suspicion", but it was only a very small amount.
疑いと言っても、本当に僅かなものです
もう一度説明しておきますが、
キラは日本に入った FBI 捜査官十二人を殺しています
Let me say it once more.
Kira has killed twelve FBI agents that were sent to this country.
They were all investigating people connected to the Japanese police force.
彼等は日本警察関係者を尾行していました
Out of all of them, Ray Penber's death stood out as being suspicious.
その中の一人、レイ．ペンバー、
彼の死に、特に不審な点が多い
And I was one of the ones he was investigating...
そして、彼が調べていた者の中に、僕がいた
I guess it can't be helped that I'm a suspect then.
これは疑われても仕方がない…
It's as Ryuuga says; there's no one else to suspect.
いや、流河の言う通り、他に疑う対象がいない
Your reasoning is quite something.
夜神君の推理力は大したものです、
It's always fast and precise.
いつも的確で速い
Ryuuga, I'll cooperate with the investigation.
流河、捜査には協力するよ
流河が L と言うことは、父が証明してくれたからね
After all, my father proved that you're L.
I'll catch Kira, and prove to you that I'm not Kira.
そしてキラを捕まえて、
僕がキラじゃないことを証明して見せるよ
I'll catch Kira, and prove to you that I'm not Kira.
Light. Right now, you should be concentrating on your studies in order to join the police force.
月
お前はこれから勉強して警察庁に入るんだ、
Light. Right now, you should be concentrating on your studies in order to join the police force.
You can start investigating after that.
その後でも遅くないんじゃないか
What are you saying, father?
何言ってるんだよ父さん、
それじゃ何年後になるか分らない
Nobody knows how many years that could take.
In any case, I've already promised that... if anything happens to you... I'll make sure Kira is sentenced to death.
それに約束したじゃないか、
父さんにもしもの事があったら、僕がキラを死刑台に送るって…
In any case, I've already promised that... if anything happens to you... I'll make sure Kira is sentenced to death.
There's no way my son is Kira.
この息子がキラであるはずがない
とても演技だと思えない
I'm sure this can't be an act.
いや、演技だとしたら臭すぎる…
No, it's too suspicious to be an act.
Listen up, Light. Kira is evil.
聞いてくれ月
キラは悪だ、それは事実だ
That's the truth.
しかし、最近私はこう思うようにもなっている…
But recently, I've been wondering what's really to blame... and it's the power to kill others.
悪いのは人を殺せる力だ
そんな力を持ってしまった人間は不幸だ
Any human that comes across that power will be unhappy.
No matter how one uses that power, you can never build true happiness on the deaths of others.
どんな使い方をしても、人を殺した上での幸せなど、
真の幸せであるはずがない
Yagami-san is correct.
夜神さんの言う通りです
If Kira is just an ordinary person that somehow acquired these powers, they are indeed unfortunate.
もしキラが普通の人間で、その力を手に入れたのなら、
まったく不幸な人間です
If Kira is just an ordinary person that somehow acquired these powers, they are indeed unfortunate.
Sorry to trouble you like this, Ryuuzaki.
竜崎、迷惑を掛けたが、できるだけ早く私も復帰する
I'll do my best to recover.
Umm.. Visiting hours are now over.
あの…
面会時間終りですよ
Ryuuga.
流河
何か僕がキラじゃないと信用してもらえる方法はないか…
Is there any way that I can prove to you that I'm not Kira?
If you aren't Kira, then there's no need for you to do that.
夜神君がキラでないのなら、
そんなことする必要ないじゃないですか
If you aren't Kira, then there's no need for you to do that.
Come off it!
いい加減にしろよ
Try thinking about how it feels to be the one accused of being Kira!
キラだと疑われる人間がどんな気持ちか…考えてみろよ
I would feel awful.
最悪の気持ちになりました
For example, you could lock me up for a month, without TV or anything, and keep me under supervision.
だから例えば、一ヶ月間、
僕をテレビも何もないところに入れて、
誰かにずっと監視させておくとか…
For example, you could lock me up for a month, without TV or anything, and keep me under supervision.
Is it normal for someone to want to clear their name this much?
普通そこまでして疑いを晴らしたいと思うだろうか…
No. I wouldn't do something that would infringe on your basic human rights like that.
ダメです、そんな人権を無視したことはできませんし、
And most importantly, it would be nonsense for me to accept the suggestion of someone who's a suspect.
何よりも疑いのかかっている者からの案を取るのは、
ナンセンスです
なるほど
I see.
It'll be alright.
大丈夫ですよ
If you aren't Kira, I'll find out sooner or later.
キラでないのなら、そのうち分ることです
Plus, having witnessed your interaction with your father today, I thought that you might not be Kira.
それに今日の夜神君と父さんのやりとりで、
キラでないとも考えました
Plus, having witnessed your interaction with your father today, I thought that you might not be Kira.
Please take care of your father.
では、お父さんをお大事に
O-One last thing.
あっ、もう一つ
I said I'd cooperate with the investigation, but until my father gets better, I don't think I can do much.
捜査協力するとは言ったけど、
父が元気になるまでは、しばらく何もできないと思う
I know.
わかってます、では…
Goodbye.
Ryuuga Hideki... Ryuuzaki... he's the L I've been fighting all along.
流河旱樹…竜崎
僕が戦ってきた L はアイツだ…
Ryuuga Hideki... Ryuuzaki... he's the L I've been fighting all along.
His real name is...
本当の名前は…
Yagami Light... are you not Kira?
夜神月…
キラではないのか
Yagami Light... are you not Kira?
Ryuk.
リューク
Hmm?
ん？
ちから
僕はノートを拾ってこの能力を得たことを…
不幸だなんて一度も思った事はない
I've never once thought of me finding this notebook as unfortunate.
I'm so happy to have this power... and I'll create a perfect world with it.
この力を得た僕は…最高に幸せだよ
そして最高の世界をつくる
ノートを持ったことで、
ライトが幸せになろうが不幸になろうが、
I don't care whether the notebook makes you happy or unhappy, Light.
そんなことはオレはどうでもいい
But, I've heard that normally, people who are haunted by Shinigami, usually end up unhappy.
ただ…
普通は死神に憑かれた人間は、不幸になるらしい…
But, I've heard that normally, people who are haunted by Shinigami, usually end up unhappy.
Well, Ryuk.
じゃあリュークは、普通じゃないほうのパターンを見られるよ
I guess you'll get to see a pattern that's not normal then.
へへ、それはありがたい
I'm thankful for that.
What's going on?!
なんなんだよ
こんな企画しか出せないのかよ
Is this the best plan ya can come up with?!
You better not be thinking that ya can get ratings by only airing programs about Kira!
おまえら、キラの特番やってれば、
なんでも視聴率とれると思ってんじゃないの？
The reason my channel has survived is because we air stories that other channels don't do!
今まで俺の番組が視聴率をとってきたのは
他の局じゃやらないネタをやってきたからなんだよ
Got it?
分ってる？問題はネタなんだよ、ネタ
The problem is getting stories.
Someone bring me a good story!
何がいいネタ持って来いよ
You say that, but the police aren't saying anything; it's impossible.
そんなこと言われても…
警察はだんまりだし、無理っすよ…
Fool! If you don't have a story, who cares if it's a fake, just make one up!
バカ！
ネタがなきゃ、がせでもいいから自分で作れっつーの
Fool! If you don't have a story, who cares if it's a fake, just make one up!
Director Demegawa, there's a special delivery for you.
出目川ディレクター、速達です
What's this?
何だこりゃ、
Who's this from?
何者からだ…
え…?!
お前らこういうんだよ、こういうの出して来いっつーんだよ
This is what I'm talking about.
This is the kind of stuff I need ya guys to come up with.
Along with proving
the fact that I am Kira
a message from Kira to the world
will also be broadcast.
If you don't air this,
I will kill off your company,
beginning with the president.
This is too much!
いや～たまんないねぇ…
A message from Kira to the world
キラから全世界へのメッセージ
「放映に逆らうようなことをしたら、
貴社の社長から殺していくことになります」ってよ…
"If you don't air this, I will kill off your company, starting off with the president", apparently!
Like I'd dare to oppose this!
逆らうかよ、これが本物だったらすげぇことになるぞ
If this is real, it's going to be amazing!
To Director Demegawa
- Sakura TV
I am Kira.
Proof is provided in video tape one.
Once you've ascertained that I am Kira,
please air tapes two to four on the
dates listed on the next page from your station.
By fore-warning people of these murders,
along with proving to society the fact that
I am Kira.
おいおい、嬉しくてどきどきが止まらないよ
I'm so excited, my heart's pumping like mad!
To be continued
今の状況なら、四日後に L が葬られる可能性は高い
やはり神は僕の味方をしている
神と言っても今回は…
死神だけどね